Guide to the Time Inc. Corporate Editorial Records 1944-2003 (bulk 1959-1994) MS 3009-RG 6
New-York Historical Society
- Series I.A. Editor-in-Chief Hedley Donovan Files, 1948-1989 (bulk 1959-1979); 56.5 Linear feet in 57 record cartons
  - Subseries I.A.6. Trips, 1952-1982; 4 Linear feet in 4 record cartons
    - Canada: Montreal, Ottawa, Toronto: October 11-14, 1971 (Offsite-box 759, Folder 33)
    - Caneel Bay: January 8-18, 1973 (Offsite-box 759, Folder 34)
    - Caneel Bay: January 16-25, 1978: Cancelled (Offsite-box 759, Folder 35)
    - Caribbean: Grenada, Martinique by charter, then Caneel Bay: January 3-19, 1972 (Offsite-box 759, Folder 36)
    - Carter, 1976 (Offsite-box 759, Folder 37)
    - Chicago: March 1961 (Offsite-box 759, Folder 38)
    - Chicago: May 5-6, 1970 (Offsite-box 759, Folder 39)
    - Chicago Annual Meeting: April 20-21, 1966 (Offsite-box 759, Folder 40)
    - Chicago Reception: November 23, 1971 (Offsite-box 759, Folder 41)
    - Chicago trip, plus Washington: September 22-25, 1975 (Offsite-box 759, Folder 42)
    - Chile, undated (Offsite-box 759, Folder 43)
    - China, 1979 (Offsite-box 759, Folder 44)
    - People's Republic of China: Peking, Hong Kong: January 20-28, 1979 (Offsite-box 759, Folder 45)
    - Boston: Choate Club: Harvard Visiting Committee: March 11-12, 1968 (Offsite-box 759, Folder 46)
    - Cleveland-Chicago Trip: October 24-29, 1967 (Offsite-box 759, Folder 47)
    - Conclusions, undated (Offsite-box 759, Folder 48)
    - Confederation of British Individuals: London: December 3-5, 1971 (Offsite-box 759, Folder 49)
    - Conference on the Presidency: Minneapolis: November 5-7, 1982 (Offsite-box 759, Folder 50)
    - Congressional Seminar: Washington, D.C.: May 19, 1975 (Offsite-box 759, Folder 51)
    - Convention: Chicago, 1952 (Offsite-box 759, Folder 52)
    - Dartmouth Conference II: With Russians: December 3-7, 1972 (Offsite-box 759, Folder 53)
    - Dartmouth Conference VIII: Soviet Union: April 21-25, 1974 (Offsite-box 759, Folder 54)
    - Dartmouth Conference VII: Carnegie endowment: Time Inc. conference on anti-trust laws: Williamsburg, Washington: May 4-8, 1979 (Offsite-box 759, Folder 55)
    - Delos Symposium and Greece: July 13-26, 1966 (Offsite-box 759, Folder 56)
    - Democratic and Republican Political Conventions: Miami Beach: July 1972 (Offsite-box 759, Folder 57)
    - Detroit-Pittsburgh: June 2-3, 1964 (Offsite-box 759, Folder 58)
    - News Tour of Eastern Europe: October 20-November 2, 1966 (Offsite-box 759, Folder 59)
    - Economy (Offsite-box 759, Folder 60)
    - England, and DD to Amsterdam: May 4-18, 1976 (DD May 22) (Offsite-box 759, Folder 61)
    - England, East Germany, Sweden: June 14-28, 1970 (Offsite-box 759, Folder 62)
    - Europe: May 4-June 14, 1955 (Offsite-box 760, Folder 1)
    - Europe: June 1959 (Offsite-box 760, Folder 2)
    - Europe: Includes London board meeting: May 12-June 9, 1963 (Offsite-box 760, Folder 3)
    - European Businessmen's Tour of the United States, 1968 (Offsite-box 760, Folder 4)
    - European sales convention and Paris: Juan Les-Pins: June 16-23, 1966 (Offsite-box 760, Folder 5)
    - European Trip: February 11-24, 1968 (Offsite-box 760, Folder 6)
    - Exxon Gulf Coast Expedition: July 8-9, 1974 (Offsite-box 760, Folder 7)
    - Far East Trip: April 8-29, 1973 (Offsite-box 760, Folder 8)
    - Far East Trip: Japan, Korea, Okinawa, Hong Kong, Vietnam: October 19-November 24, 1965 (Offsite-box 760, Folder 9-10)
    - Florida primary trip: Tampa-Miami: March 8-11, 1972: Cancelled (Offsite-box 760, Folder 11)
    - Foliage watching: Williamstown-Bucks County: October 15-19, 1971 (Offsite-box 760, Folder 12)
    - Foreign Policy Seminar: Washington, D.C.: November 11-12, 1974 (Offsite-box 760, Folder 13)
    - France-Germany: May 21-June 11, 1977 (Offsite-box 760, Folder 14)
    - Harvard and Yale: April 7-9, 1970 (Offsite-box 760, Folder 15)
    - Hawaii, Los Angeles, San Francisco: September 20-24, 1968, 1968, undated (Offsite-box 760, Folder 16)
    - Hedley Donovan trip: June 1977 (Offsite-box 760, Folder 17)
    - Hilton Head, South Carolina: March 21-31, 1969 (Offsite-box 760, Folder 18)
    - Houston: Board meeting: September 15-17, 1970 (Offsite-box 760, Folder 19)
    - Indianapolis trip: December 1-2, 1969 (Offsite-box 760, Folder 20)
    - Indonesia: February 1967 (Offsite-box 760, Folder 21)
    - Ireland: Reading: June 6, 1972 (Offsite-box 760, Folder 22)
    - Italy: October 1961 (Offsite-box 760, Folder 23)
    - Jamaica and St. John Vacation: January 1-13 and January 18-25, 1970 (Offsite-box 760, Folder 24)
    - Japan: October 1965 (Offsite-box 760, Folder 25)
    - Johnson, President Lyndon B.: Weekend at the LBJ ranch: December 16-18, 1966 (Offsite-box 760, Folder 26)
    - Johnson, President Lyndon B.: Weekend at Ranch: December 1966, 1966, undated (Offsite-box 760, Folder 27)
    - Khrushchev, undated (Offsite-box 760, Folder 28)
    - Lake Mohonk: Carnegie Endowment Trustee's meeting: May 22-24, 1970 (Offsite-box 760, Folder 29)
    - Life Space Tour: November 29-December 5, 1964 (Offsite-box 760, Folder 30)
    - Life Space Tour: March 27-30, 1966 (Offsite-box 760, Folder 31)
    - Little Brown Reception: Daedalus Meeting: Boston: October 31-November 2, 1968 (Offsite-box 760, Folder 32)
    - London, January 9-13, 1963 (Offsite-box 760, Folder 33)
    - London, Germany, Paris: Interiors, contacts: June 1959 (Offsite-box 760, Folder 34)
    - London, India, Bangkok, Djakarta, Singapore, Australia: February 5-March 1, 1967 (Offsite-box 760, Folder 35-37)
    - London, Middle East (Cairo, Ammani, Damascus, Baghdad), Rome: December 30, 1978-January 16, 1979, 1978-1979 (Offsite-box 760, Folder 38)
    - London, Paris, Germany trip: February 11-24, 1968 (Offsite-box 760, Folder 39)
    - London, Paris trip notes: December 1968 (Offsite-box 760, Folder 40)
    - London, Paris, Bonn, Rome, Procigano: September 22-October 14, 1974 (Offsite-box 760, Folder 41)
    - Los Angeles: November 1960 (Offsite-box 760, Folder 42)
    - Los Angeles: La Jolla: December 5-13, 1964 (Offsite-box 760, Folder 43)
    - Los Angeles Conference: September 30-October 1, 1972 (Offsite-box 760, Folder 44)
    - Media and Society seminar: Philadelphia: April 2-4, 1982 (Offsite-box 760, Folder 45)
    - Mexico: September 8-10, 1965 (Offsite-box 760, Folder 46)
    - Mexico: Cozumel-Yucatan: January 12-26, 1974: Cancelled (Offsite-box 760, Folder 47)
    - Mexico: Yucatan-Cancun-Cozumel: February 5-17, 1975 (Offsite-box 760, Folder 48)
    - Mid East Trip: March 21-28, 1980 (Offsite-box 761, Folder 1)
    - Middle East Trip: Egypt-Moscow-Rome-Israel: April 28-May 14, 1969 (Offsite-box 761, Folder 2)
    - Middle East Trip: February 28-March 17, 1974 (Offsite-box 761, Folder 3)
    - Middle East News Tour: January 17-30, 1975 (Offsite-box 761, Folder 4)
    - Minneapolis: March 1961 (Offsite-box 761, Folder 5)
    - Minneapolis: May 1962 (Offsite-box 761, Folder 6)
    - Minneapolis: March 2-7, 1965 (Offsite-box 761, Folder 7)
    - Minneapolis: May 1968 (Offsite-box 761, Folder 8)
    - Minneapolis: April 22-25, 1971 (Offsite-box 761, Folder 9)
    - Minneapolis and Chicago trip: November 18-20, 1969: November 19 Board Meeting (Offsite-box 761, Folder 10)
    - Minneapolis-Chicago: August 16-19, 1970 (Offsite-box 761, Folder 11)
    - Minneapolis-Chicago: January 10-12, 1971 (Offsite-box 761, Folder 12)
    - Minneapolis-Chicago: University of Minneapolis Foundation: October 26-29, 1973 (Offsite-box 761, Folder 13)
    - M.I.T.: A: March 1977 (Offsite-box 761, Folder 14)
    - M.I.T.: With Louis Banks: Cambridge: April 14-16, 1977 (Offsite-box 761, Folder 15)
    - Moline, IL-Columbia, MO: April 23-26, 1975 (Offsite-box 761, Folder 16)
    - NATO Trip: Rome, Brussels, Bonn, Nuremberg, Stuttgart: June 17-27, 1981 (Offsite-box 761, Folder 17)
    - New England weekend: October 18-20, 1973 (Offsite-box 761, Folder 18)
    - North Carolina Time Inc. Seminar: November 11-13, 1978 (Offsite-box 761, Folder 19)
    - O.I.U.H.C. Reunion: Montreal: September 17-19, 1976 (Offsite-box 761, Folder 20)
    - Offutt Air Base Sac: April 23-24, 1964 (Offsite-box 761, Folder 21)
    - Okinawa: October 23, 1965 (Offsite-box 761, Folder 22)
    - Overseas trips, Summary of, undated (Offsite-box 761, Folder 23)
    - Panama, 1975, undated (Offsite-box 761, Folder 24)
    - Paris: October 1960 (Offsite-box 761, Folder 25)
    - Paris-Amsterdam: European Bureau Meeting, Paris: Europe-America Conference, Amsterdam: March 23-18, 1973 (Offsite-box 761, Folder 26)
    - Paris, India, Rome, London: Ford Foundation Meeting, India: September 17-October 19, 1978 (Offsite-box 761, Folder 27)
    - Pearl Harbor-Korea-Hong Kong, China: October-November 1965 (Offsite-box 761, Folder 28)
    - Pebble Beach, CA: Sports Illustrated sales meeting: September 17-19, 1973 (Offsite-box 761, Folder 29)
    - Peru, undated (Offsite-box 761, Folder 30)
    - Phoenix, AZ: April 1962 (Offsite-box 761, Folder 31)
    - Political swing: Kansas City-Des Moines-Urbana-Springfield-Milwaukee: September 12-20, 1972 (Offsite-box 761, Folder 32)
    - Post-trip correspondence and items: India-Australia-Far East trip: February 5-March 1, 1967 (Offsite-box 761, Folder 33)
    - Qantas. round-the-world: December 1957-January 1958, 1957-1958 (Offsite-box 761, Folder 34)
    - Republican Convention, Kansas City: August 15-20, 197 (Offsite-box 761, Folder 35)
    - Rome-Moscow: October 17-November 2, 1980 (Offsite-box 761, Folder 36)
    - Rome-Naples: May 19-June 4, 1978 (Offsite-box 761, Folder 37)
    - Russia notes: Interviews about the U.S.S.R. in general, 1958, undated (Offsite-box 761, Folder 38)
    - Russian News Tours: Never happened, 1967-1968 (Offsite-box 761, Folder 39)
    - Russian notes, 1968 (Offsite-box 761, Folder 40)
    - Russian trip: January 13-24, 1968 (Offsite-box 761, Folder 41)
    - Russian trip: Research and notes: April 19-May 5, 1974 (Offsite-box 761, Folder 42)
    - Russia-Siberia: Dartmouth VIII conference with Russians: April 19-May 4, 1974 (Offsite-box 761, Folder 43)
    - St. John Vacation: January 22-February 2, 1971 (Offsite-box 761, Folder 44)
    - St. Louis: September 1960 (Offsite-box 761, Folder 45)
    - St. Louis-Detroit-Chicago: October 19-20, 1964 (Offsite-box 761, Folder 46)
    - Saint Maarten: December 23-30, 1978 (Offsite-box 761, Folder 47)
    - "Security", undated (Offsite-box 761, Folder 48)
    - September-October 1978 (Offsite-box 761, Folder 49)
    - South Africa-Kenya-Frankfurt: Ford Foundation Board Meeting: September 16-October 10, 1982 (Offsite-box 761, Folder 50)
    - South American trip: October 16-November 2, 1975 (Offsite-box 761, Folder 51)
    - South American trip and Time essay: Background material and research: October 7-November 7, 1975 (Offsite-box 761, Folder 52)
    - Sterling Forest-Washington-Nassau: December 7-13, 1970 (Offsite-box 761, Folder 53)
    - Stonehenge: The Role of Technology in the Growth of Time Inc.: October 7-8, 1968 (Offsite-box 761, Folder 54)
    - Super Bowl, New Orleans: January 10-13, 1975 (Offsite-box 761, Folder 55)
    - Super Bowl, New Orleans: January 13-16, 1978 (Offsite-box 761, Folder 56)
    - Time Asia News Tour: February 20-March 9, 1969 (Offsite-box 761, Folder 57)
    - Time (Envelope): Hotel Saint-Georges: Beirut, Lebanon, 1978 (Offsite-box 761, Folder 58)
    - Time Inc. conference on taxation: September 12-14, 1978 (Offsite-box 761, Folder 59)
    - Time News Tour Participants, 1975 (Offsite-box 761, Folder 60)
    - Time: Reports on America: October 3-8, 1971 (Offsite-box 761, Folder 61)
    - Traverse City-Los Angeles: June 7-11, 1975 (Offsite-box 761, Folder 62)
    - Turkey-Ireland: May 25-June 11, 1972 (Offsite-box 761, Folder 63)
    - Venezuela, 1975 (Offsite-box 761, Folder 64)
    - Vermont Weekend: October 1-4, 1976 (Offsite-box 761, Folder 65)
    - Vietnam notes: October 1965 (Offsite-box 761, Folder 66)
    - Vietnam trip: April 21-May 4, 1967 (Offsite-box 762, Folder 1)
    - Washington: April 18-21, 1970 (Offsite-box 762, Folder 2)
    - Washington: Gridiron Dinner: March 12-14, 1971, 1971, undated (Offsite-box 762, Folder 3)
    - Washington: July 1981 (Offsite-box 762, Folder 4)
    - Washington, D.C.: June 27-28, 1968 (Offsite-box 762, Folder 5)
    - Washington, D.C.: July 14-16, 1975 (Offsite-box 762, Folder 6)
    - Washington, D.C.: January 11-13, 1976 (Offsite-box 762, Folder 7)
    - Washington and fall leaf trip: October 3-7, 1975 (Offsite-box 762, Folder 8)
    - Washington trips, 1953 (Offsite-box 762, Folder 9)
    - Why Supreme Soviet, Elections, undated (Offsite-box 762, Folder 10)
  - Subseries I.A.7. Audiovisual, 1966-1977; 2 Linear feet in 2 record cartons
    Audiovisual contains audiotape reels and audio cassettes of primarily speeches by or events attended by Hedley Donovan.
    Organized chronologically with undated material at the end.
    Access Restrictions
    Unreformatted audiovisual material in the collection is not accessible.
    - 1966 November 3 (Offsite-box 784, Folder 1)
      1 audiotape reel: analog, 1/4 in. tape. On container label: "Copy. University Foundation. Side 1 11/3/66."
    - 1966 December 20 (Offsite-box 784, Folder 2)
      1 audiotape reel: analog, 1 7/8 ips. On container label: "Donovan Luncheon 12/20/66."
    - 1967 January 11 (Offsite-box 784, Folder 3)
      1 audiotape reel: analog, 3 3/4 ips. On front container label: "Talk - Hedley Donovan. Jan 11, '67. Congregational Church of Manhasset." On back container label: "Track 1 only."
    - 1968 January 26 (Offsite-box 784, Folder 4)
      1 audiotape reel: analog, 7 in., 1/4 in. tape. On container label: "Donovan 1/26/68."
    - 1969 February 18 (Offsite-box 784, Folder 5)
      1 audiotape reel: analog, 3 3/4 ips. On label: "Occasion: Centennial Banquet. Place: Sheraton-Cleveland Hotel. Introductions: Herbert E. Strawbridge, Thomas Vail. Introducing Hedley Donovan Editor-in-Chief Time Inc. Recorder: E. Jones. C.P.L."
    - 1969 December 1 (Offsite-box 784, Folder 6)
      1 audiotape reel: analog, 3 3/4 ips; monaural; halftrack; 5 in., 1/4 in. tape. On container label: "Hedley Donovan Speech-Indianapolis 12/1/69."
      1 audiotape reel: analog, 3 3/4 ips; monaural; halftrack; 5 in., 1/4 in. tape. On container label: "Hedley Donovan question and answer period following speech in Indianapolis 12/1/69."
    - 1970 March (Offsite-box 784, Folder 7)
      1 audiotape reel: analog. On container label: "Detroit speech March '70 and question and answers with Council on Foreign Relations."
      1 audiotape reel: analog.
    - 1970 March 17 (Offsite-box 784, Folder 8)
      1 audiotape reel: analog, 7 in., 1/4 in. tape. On container label: "Editors and Managers for the Early '70's. Speech delivered by Hedley Donovan, Editor-in-Chief - Time, Inc. to Distinguished Visitors Series Society for Advancement of Management, Twin City Chapter. March 17, 1970."
    - 1970 November 17 (Offsite-box 784, Folder 9)
      1 audiotape reel: analog, 3 3/4ips; 4in. On container label: "Hedley Donovan Wildlife Congress Speech, Nov 17."
    - 1971 October 7 (Offsite-box 784, Folder 10)
      1 audiotape reel: analog. On container label: "10/7/71 This is an empty tape. Rhodes Scholar Dinner dud."
    - 1971 October 8 (Offsite-box 784, Folder 11)
      1 audiotape reel: analog, 1 7/8 ips; 1/4 in. tape. On container label: "10-8-71 Couples Club. Congregational Church of Manhasset."
    - 1972 February 5 (Offsite-box 784, Folder 12)
      1 audiotape reel: analog, 5 in., 1/4 in. tape. On container label: "Eagle Scout Lunch. Feb 5, 1972. Minneapolis."
    - 1972 October 13 (Offsite-box 784, Folder 13)
      1 audiotape reel: analog, On container label: "October 13, 1972. Minikahda Club. Minneapolis"
    - 1974 January 3 (Offsite-box 784, Folder 14)
      1 audiotape reel: analog, 7 in., 1/4 in. tape. On container label: Illegible handwriting and "Talk to former Life edit staffer. 8th flr. auditorium. 1/3/74."
    - 1974 December 12 (Offsite-box 784, Folder 15)
      1 audiotape reel: analog, 1/4 in. tape. On container label: "Hedley Donovan. Time Inc. staff mtg. December 12, 1974. 8th flr auditorium."
    - 1975 April 23 (Offsite-box 784, Folder 16)
      1 audiotape reel: analog. On container label: "H. Donovan speech - Deere & Co. 'America and the World Out There.' April 23, 1975."
    - 1975 June 19 (Offsite-box 785, Folder 1)
      1 audiotape reel: analog, 1/4 in. tape. On container label: "Hedley Donovan. Time Inc. staff talk. June 19, 1975."
    - 1976 March 18 (Offsite-box 785, Folder 2)
      1 audiotape reel: analog, 1/4 in. tape. On container label: "Hedley Donovan talk to staff meeting in auditorium. 3/18/76 4:30 pm."
    - 1976 March 23 (Offsite-box 785, Folder 3)
      1 audiotape reel: analog, 7 in., 1/4 in. tape. On container label: "World Affairs Council -- Boston, March 23, 1976."
    - 1976 June 2 (Offsite-box 785, Folder 4)
      1 audiocassette (Sony DC-90): analog. On label: "June 2, 1976. Hedley Donovan talk to Chicago Council on Foreign Rel."
    - 1976 October 6 (Offsite-box 785, Folder 5)
      1 audiotape reel: analog, 7 1/2 ips. On container label: "Reel 1. Bohemian Club Art Gallery. 10-6-76. 7 1/2 ips / 1/2 track. Recorded on both sides. HD Speech -- San Francisco. Business and the Press."
      1 audiotape reel: analog, 7 1/2 ips. On container label: "Reel 2. Bohemian Club Art Gallery. 10-6-76. 7 1/2 ips / 1/2 track. Recorded on one side only."
    - 1977 April 27 (Offsite-box 785, Folder 6)
      1 audiotape reel: analog, 1/4 in. tape. On container label: " Money staff meeting. April 27, 1977."
      1 audiotape reel: analog, 1/4 in. tape. On container label: " Money staff meeting. (second tape). April 27, 1977."
    - 1977 May 19 (Offsite-box 785, Folder 7)
      1 audiotape reel: analog, 3 3/4 ips; 1/4 in. tape. On container label: "Speed 3 3/4. Date 5/19/77. Subject: Fortune's. Place: 47th Floor T&L Bldg. Speakers. H. Donovan 0000 to 0380 on 3 3/4. Lubar 0381."
    - Undated (Offsite-box 785, Folder 8)
      1 audiotape reel: analog, 7 in., 1/4 in. tape. On container label: "Tuesday May 21. Hedley Donovan. Fortune Ponte Vedra. Convention Speech."
    - Undated (Offsite-box 785, Folder 9)
      1 audiotape reel: analog. On container label: "Hedley Donovan's Speech at A.I.M.E. Banquet."
    - Undated (Offsite-box 785, Folder 10)
      1 audiocassette (recoton 90): analog in., 3 7/8 x 2 1/2 in., 1/8 in. tape. Labeled side 1 and side 2.
      1 audiocassette (Scotch C-60): analog, 3 7/8 x 2 1/2 in., 1/8 in. tape. On container label: "Grunwald. To be returned to Anne Rhoads in Alex Burnham's office - Room 2339."
      1 audiocassette (Norelco C-60): analog, 3 7/8 x 2 1/2 in., 1/8 in. tape. On container label: "Revised for air - 3/24. 'On Target Every Day with 4 1/2 million readers.' Tony Burton. Ella Elvin [?]. Didi Olive [?]. Phil Rizenburgh [?]. Burt Shanus [?]." Accompanying note states these are a sample of Daily News reporters talking about their work.
    - Undated (Offsite-box 785, Folder 11)
      2 audiotape reels, analog, 7 in., 1/4 in. tape. On container label: "1st tape."
    - Undated (Offsite-box 785, Folder 12)
      1 audiotape reel: analog, 7 in., 1/4 in. tape. On container label: "2nd tape."
    - Undated (Offsite-box 785, Folder 13)
      1 audiocassette: analog, 1 7/8 ips; 3 7/8 x 2 1/2 in., 1/8 in. tape. On label side 1: "Program #8 'The Course of Human Events.' Part 1 28:09 OQ:SQI Thank you all." On label side 2: "Program #8 'The Course of Human Events.' Audience. Part 2 OQ: For group W. 24:19."
    - Undated (Offsite-box 785, Folder 14)
      1 audiotape reel: analog, 3 3/4 ips; 1/4 in. tape. On container label: "3 3/4 I.P.S. 'Caduceus [?] Society Banquet.' Side # I. Introduction by Frederic T. Kirkham Jr., MD. 'Speaker' Hedley Donovan Editor in chief - Time Inc. 'Relationships of USA & Russia'."
  - Subseries I.A.8. Personal: Memoirs Typescript, 1989; 0.5 Linear feet in 5 folders (Offsite-box 2593, Folder 1-5)
    Scope and Contents
    Contains a draft of his 1989 memoir Right Places, Right Times: 40 Years In Journalism, Not Counting My Paper Route, with the working title of Shameless Enjoyments, Disputed Powers, sent directly to Time Inc. Archivist Elaine Felsher by Donovan's literary legal representation.
    In original order.
- Series I.B. Editor-in-Chief Henry Anatole Grunwald Files, 1944-1998 (bulk 1968-1987); 75 Linear feet in 75 record cartons
  Henry Anatole Grunwald began his career at Time Inc. in 1944 as a copy boy and worked to the top editorial position of Editor-in-Chief.
  Grunwald emigrated to the United States from Austria in 1940 at the age of 17. After graduating from New York University in 1944, he began his first job at Time Inc. Grunwald held positions as a foreign correspondent from 1945 to 1951, Time Senior Editor from 1951 to 1966, Time Assistant Managing Editor from 1966 to 1968, Time Managing Editor from 1968 to 1977, Corporate Editor from 1977 to 1979, and finally was appointed as Editor-in-Chief in 1979 by his predecessor Hedley Donovan. He also served on Time Inc.'s board. Grunwald retired from Time Inc. in 1987.
  During his tenure as Editor-in-Chief, Grunwald appointed the first woman managing editor of a major Time Inc. magazine when Patricia Ryan took over People in 1982.
  Shortly after his retirement, President Ronald Reagan named Grunwald U.S. ambassador to Austria. Beginning in 1997, Grunwald published two memoirs, One Man's America, recounting his experiences as a Jewish refugee from Nazi-controlled Europe and success in his adopted country, and Twilight: Losing Sight, Gaining Insight about his degenerative loss of eyesight. In 2003, he published the novel A Saint, More or Less.
  Schudel, Matt. "Henry Grunwald, Managing Editor of Time Magazine, Dies." The Washington Post. February 27, 2005. Accessed August 29, 2017. http://www.washingtonpost.com/wp-dyn/articles/A56472-2005Feb26.html.
  Severo, Richard. "Henry A. Grunwald, Editor Who Brought Change to Time Magazine, Dies at 82." The New York Times. February 27, 2005. Accessed May 28, 2021. https://www.nytimes.com/2005/02/27/business/media/henry-a-grunwald-editor-who-brought-change-to-time-magazine.html.
  The Henry Anatole Grunwald Files primarily date from his roles at Time magazine as Senior Editor, Assistant Managing Editor, and Managing Editor; and roles at the corporate level as Editorial Director and Editor-in-Chief. Based on the accompanying archives transfer forms, all of Grunwald's files were transferred by his office while he was Editor-in-Chief. Therefore the records are not separated based on office and title, but kept in the series designated by his office on the transfer forms. Records include his internal and external correspondence, departmental files, files on Newstours he attended, speeches, and travel records.
  In 2004, shortly before Grunwald's death, his files were reviewed by a family representative and parts were removed to return to his family. In most instances, photocopies take their place. In some instances, there are notes from Time Inc. librarian C. Weil indicating what was removed. Removals include "items of personal nature, family, real estate on Vineyard."
  Organized into eight subseries:
  Subseries I.B.1. General Correspondence
  Subseries I.B.2. Interoffice Correspondence
  Subseries I.B.3. Departmental Files
  Subseries I.B.4. Newstours
  Subseries I.B.5. Photographs
  Subseries I.B.6. Speeches
  Subseries I.B.7. Trips
  Subseries I.A.8. Archives Transfer Forms
  - Subseries I.B.1. General Correspondence, 1944-1987; 14 Linear feet in 14 record cartons